### **MATTHEW O'LEARY**

olearystudios.com | linkedin.com/in/olearystudios | 831-234-7766 | mattosurf@gmail.com

# **Professional Summary**

Skilled Senior UX Designer with over 10 years of experience providing user-centered experience and interface design in a number of industries. Extensive experience in all aspects of UX and Product Design including visual design for native, web and mobile applications, user testing and research, asset and spec creation, and team leadership. Continually exceeds expectations by building valuable relationships and works well with people at all levels of an organization, including stakeholders, management, team members, and clients.

#### **Skills**

- User-Centered Experience & Interaction Design
- Adobe XD Rapid Design & Prototyping
- Usability Testing & Research
- Accessibility & Inclusivity
- UI & Visual Design
- Design Systems
- Product Copy
- Information Architecture
- Typography & Layout Expertise
- User Flows & Wireframes
- Excellent Verbal & Written Communication
- Sketch App, InVision & Zeplin Workflows
- Design Thinking

### **Work History**

#### Senior UX Designer | 2018 to Current

Axway - Santa Clara, CA

- Overseeing all user experience and design aspects for the organization working with the design and creative teams to develop a cohesive experience throughout platforms in order to increase user satisfaction.
- Leading product design for web, tablet, and Android or iOS phone applications while writing micro-copy and calls to action, creating assets and delivering final assets to developers along with clear specifications.
- Transforming product requirements and stories into user flows using a combination of discussions, whiteboarding, or sketching for information architecture, wireframing, and prototyping with rapid revisions and experimentation.
- Leading UX, visual, and information design for mobile or web products serving as the voice of UX to influence design thinking across the company while engaging with product and design teams throughout definition, research, analysis and synthesis.
- Establishing usability testing program with customers onsite or moderated including remote unmoderated usability testing with usertest.io to ensure that UX solutions meet

- client and end user needs or expectations.
- Defining research goals and identifying target users by working cross-functionally with design, product management, content strategy, engineering and marketing to design clean, intuitive, and innovative interfaces.
- Leading formal or informal critiques resulting in concise and actionable action plans applying hands-on experience in web UX design and creation of wireframes, functional desktop, mobile, and tablet prototypes.

#### Senior UX Designer | 2014 to 2018

Accellion – Palo Alto, CA

- Guided the entirety of the design process through its completion by presenting UX design solutions to stakeholders and working alongside developers to ensure accurate implementation.
- Led a team of designers and coached the team through reviews and feedback, supporting their UX/UI growth while raising the capacity, skills, and quality of user-centered design on the team.
- Applied user flow and mapped out pathways an individual would take in a website or
  platform as well as created affinity diagrams at any time during the pre-design process,
  successfully performing task analyses.
- Led user testing with customers and iterated based on feedback, leading accessibility audits and driving necessary changes for 508 compliance, creating assets and delivering final assets to developers along with clear specifications.
- Developed and lead the design team to improve the range of research methods used while employing design thinking and questioning techniques to develop strategies and execution plans where pathways were not always obvious.
- Interviewed target audiences and recorded their responses to be archived and used later in the process as well as developed personas and created profiles for particular users based on characteristics.
- Mapped storyboards to show and display a user's story, effectively mapping use cases to state why a person would use the platform and successfully using and applying wireframes in order to interface concepts.

#### Creative Lead | 2011 to 2014

FastPencil - Campbell, CA

- Developed overall flow, interactions, and visual design of FastPencil 2.0 including a complete refresh of the cloud-based publishing platform and created HTML prototypes that were used to successfully sell the brandable publishing platform.
- Art-directed freelance designers and illustrators, designing book covers for authors and templates for automatic book creation as well as wrote support documentation for FastPencil 2.0.
- Critiqued in-progress design work, evaluating the priority and effectivity of solutions while providing and encouraging feedback from the team and other designers, studying analytics to understand user behavior.
- Designed marketing communications, landing pages, email campaigns, or author web

- pages, partnering with the creative team and developers to maintain a cohesive design and experience throughout product development, providing expertise and mentorship.
- Directed and motivated teams of art directors, illustrators, and copywriters, leading brainstorming or creative sessions to generate ideas as well as revising content or presentations, approving or rejecting ideas, and providing feedback to the team.

#### **Technical Skills**

CSS, HTML, Frameworks (11ty), Foundation, Bootstrap, GitHub, WordPress, Microsoft Office

# **Training & Education**

- Emotional Design Psychology & Neuroscience Course with Brian Cugelman
- Cooper U's Visual Interface Design: Goal-directed Visual Design Process
- Fine Arts studies including Scientific Illustration, Life Drawing, Painting, and Art History at University of California, Santa Cruz
- Graphic Design Department Coursework in Design, Color Theory, Airbrush, Silkscreen,
   2- and 3-D Fundamentals, and Typography at San Jose State University
- Production Techniques for the Graphic Artist Series, Advanced Photoshop Composition and Color Theory and Expression Workshops at University of California, Santa Cruz Extension
- Breakthrough Thinking
- Frontline Management

### Links

Portfolio: <a href="https://olearystudios.com">https://olearystudios.com</a>

Linkedin: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/olearystudios">https://www.linkedin.com/in/olearystudios</a>

Email: http://mailto:mattosurf@gmail.com

More Design Samples & References available upon request